Inventory of the Philip Lightfoot Papers 1765-1860
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Philip Lightfoot Papers, 1765-1860
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.1 L62
1,277 items.
Letters and papers of the Lightfoot family of Virginia, 1765-1860, including chiefly military, legal and business papers.
Philip Lightfoot, fl. 1778-1800,; Philip Lightfoot, Jr.; William Wirt, ;; Lightfoot family.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchased: 1,277 items, 1938.
Acc. No. 1997.61; Gift: 1 item, 1997.
Biographical/Historical Information
Philip Lightfoot of Culpeper County, Virginia served as a lieutenant in the Continental Army Artillery from 1778-1781. He was commissioned as lieutenant in the Virginia militia and as captain in the 8th U. S. Infantry Regiment. His heir [Philip Lightfoot, Jr.] put in a claim for his Revolutionary War service pension in 1831 so he was apparently dead by that year.
Scope and Content Information
Papers of Philip Lightfoot of Culpeper County, Virginia including his commissions as lieutenant in the Second Battalion, 5th Regiment, Virginia militia and as captain in the 8th U. S. Infantry Regiment and papers relating to his service in the U. S. Army including records of a recruiting party, enlistment pledges, muster rolls, records of rewards offered for deserters and descriptions of U. S. Army uniforms. There are legal papers in the collection and accounts and business correspondence of merchants in Culpeper (James L. Markham, Samuel Porter, and Merrick Starr). Apparently, the later papers in the collection belong to another Philip Lightfoot [perhaps a son.] One of the two men or perhaps, both, were lawyers. The collection contains a letter, 5 July 1809, written by William Wirt as well as four pages of genealogical information on the Lightfoot family including slave births.
Arrangement
Organization
The collection is organized into 9 series: 1. Military papers of Philip Lightfoot; 2. Letters; 3. Accounts and invoices; 4. Papers relating to accounts collected by Philip Lightfoot; 5. Legal papers; 6. Papers of James L. Markham; 7. Papers of Samuel Porter; 8. Papers of Merrick Starr; 9. Miscellaneous.
Arrangement
Series 2, 6 and 7 are arranged chronologically; series 3-5 are arranged alphabetically.
Index Terms
Family name:
Lightfoot family.
Corporate name:
United States. Army. Infantry, 8th (1796-1802).
Subjects:
Lawyers--Virginia--Culpeper.; Merchants--Virginia--Culpeper.; Slavery-- Virginia.
Geographical name:
Virginia--Militia.
Persons:
Wirt, William, 1772- 1834.; Lightfoot, Philip, Jr.
Contents List
  Series 1: Military papers of Philip Lightfoot
- Military papers of Philip Lightfoot, 1794-1807, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1-3)
  - General papers, 1794-1800, 1814, n.d. (Box-folder 1:1-2)
    - A roll of the company of light infantry, 2nd Bataillion, 5th Regiment, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Recruiting records of Philip Lightfoot, 1799-1800., 7 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Pay roll of Philip Lightfoot' company, 8th United States Regiment, 1799., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Copy of a receipt for pay, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Muster roll of Philip Lightfoot's company, 8th United States Regiment, 1799-1800., 3 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - An invoice for services rendered to soldiers in Captain Philip Lightfoot's company, 1799., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Records relating to supplies for Captain Philip Lightfoot's company, 1799-1800., 3 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Regulations for the delivery and distribution of fuel and straw to the garrisons on the sea coast and recruiting parties, 1799., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - General orders, 1799., 3 items. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Orderly book of Captain Philip Lightfoot containing general, divisional and brigade orders and instruction and records of courts martial, 19 September 1799 - 13 January 1800., 7 3/4" x 13". 90 pages. (Box-folder 1:1)
      An entry for 21 December 1799 gives a detailed description of the uniforms of the United States.
    - Orderly book of Captain Philip Lightfoot containing general, divisional and brigade orders and records of courts martial, 7 January 1800 - 31 March 1800, 8" x 12 1/4". 92 pages. (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Orderly book of Captain Philip Lightfoot containing general, divisional and brigade orders and records of courts martial, 3 April 1800 - 7 June 1800, 7 1/2" x 13". 92 pages. (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Reports of camp guards, company not indicated, 1800., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Memoranda concerning paroles, countersigns and watch-words, 1814., 3 items. (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Records of the court martial of Captain R. S. Blackburn, 1799-1800., 7 items. (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Records of other courts martial, 1794-1800., 4 items. (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Advertisement offering rewards for the return of deserters, n.d., mutilated, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Correspondence, 1798-1807. (Box-folder 1:3)
    chronological
    - John Marshall, at Richmond, to James McHenry, the Secretary of War, at Philadelphia, 10 August 1798., Autograph copy signed. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - James McHenry, War Department, to [?], 1 April 1799., Circular letter. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Thomas Parker, Frederick County, to Capt. Philip Lightfoot, Culpeper County, 22 April 1799. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Thomas Parker, at Winchester, to Capt. Philip Lightfoot, Culpeper County, 26 May 1799. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Lemuel Bent, at Winchester, to Capt. Philip Lightfoot, at Woodstock, Shenandoah County, 2 July 1799. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Lawrence Butler, at Winchester, to Capt. Philip Lightfoot, at Woodstock, 10 July 1799 and 30 July 1799., Mutilated. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Henry Lee, at Richmond, to Captains Green, Slaughter, Jett, and Voss, appointed to command the several companies of light infantry in Culpeper, 5 August 1799. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Lawrence Butler, at Winchester, to Capt. Philip Lightfoot, at Woodstock, 21 August 1799. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Lawrence Butler, at Winchester, to Thomas Jameson, at Woodstock, 28 August 1799. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Thomas Mason, Fairfax County, to Philip Lightfoot, Culpeper County, Virginia, 21 November 1806 and 1 December 1806. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Thomas Mason, Fairfax County, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 13 September 1807. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Commissions of Philip Lightfoot, 1794, 1799. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Appointment as Lieutenant in a company of light infantry, second Battalion, 5th Regiment of Virginia State Militia, 1794., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:3)
      Signed by Henry Lee.
    - Letter from James McHenry, announcing his appointment as a captain of infantry in the the army of the United States, 1799., 1 item. (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Printed Matter, 1799, n.d. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Adams (John) Rules and Regulations respecting the recruiting service, 14, [6] pages. 24 1/2 cm. (Box-folder 1:3)
      The forms in this manual are filled in with ink and dated 5 April 1799.
    - Steubens Exercise., 95 pages, 16 cm. Mutilated. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Pamphlet giving diagrams for military drill., 14 1/2 cm x 34 1/2 cm. 8 sheets. (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Two blank forms., Mutilated. (Box-folder 1:3)
  Series 2: Letters
- Letters, 1793-1860, n.d. (Box-folder 2:4-5)
  chronologically
  - James Duncanson, at Fredericksburg, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 8 January 1793. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - John Strode to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 12 January 1793. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Philip R. Thompson, at Richmond, to Edward Stevens, Jr., and Philip Lightfoot, Jr., at Culpeper Court House, 8 December 1793. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - John B. Lightfoot to his brother, Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 26 February 1794. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Elizabeth Field and Frances Lightfoot, at Mason, Kentucky, to E. Stevens, P. Lightfoot and A. Camp, at Culpeper Court House, 9 August 1794. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Edward Lightfoot, Mason County, Kentucky, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, August 1794. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Frances Lightfoot, at Baregrass, Jefferson County, Kentucky, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 2 June 1795. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - John Strode to Philip Lightfoot, at Fairfax Town, Culpeper County, 17 July 1795. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Garland Thompson, at Hanover, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 11 April 1796. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Francis Taylor, at Washington, Kentucky, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 17 May 1797; 13 February 1798. (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Edward Lightfoot, Jefferson County, Kentucky, to his brother, Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 20 March 1798. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Philip Lightfoot, at Woodstock, Shenandoah County, Virginia, to Richard Y. Wigginton, Culpeper County, 12 July 1799. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - B. Shackelford, at Culpeper Court House, to Captain Philip Lightfoot, 8th U. S. Regiment, at Woodstock, 5 August 1799. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - John Jameson, Culpeper County, to Philip Lightfoot, at Woodstock, 7 August 1799. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - [?] Clagett, at Culpeper Court House, to Capt. Philip Lightfoot, at Harper's Ferry, 21 October 1799. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Benjamin Day, Grand Master, Lodge of Virginia, at Fredericksburg, to Capt. Philip Lightfoot, at Harper's Ferry, Berkeley County, 15 May 1800. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - John G. Brown, at Lewisburg, to Capt. Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 21 July 1800. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Daniel Lee, at Woodstock, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 26 July 1800. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, to Hugh Holmes, at Winchester, 15 May 1802. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - James Threlkeld, agent for James Lendrum, to John Shackleford, 9 July 1803. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, to Philip P. Wilson, at Martinsburg, Berkeley County, 25 July 1803. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Philip Lightfoot, at Fairfax Town, Culpeper County, to Ferdinando Fairfax, at Charles Town, Jefferson County, Septmeber 1803., Mutilated. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - John Brown, at Richmond, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 13 December 1803. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Enclosure: List of fees in Madison County, due John Brown, clerk of the Court of Appeals, 1794-1802.
  - Daniel Lee, at Woodstock, to Philip Lightfoot, 25 September 1804. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Goodrich Lightfoot to his brother, Major Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 27 October 1805. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Robert Coleman, Jefferson County, Kentucky, to Philip Lightfoot, Culpeper County, Virginia, 3 December 1805. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Daniel Lee, at Winchester, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 23 September 1806. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - George Hay, at Richmond, to James Byrne, Mayor of Petersburg, 20 August 1808. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Daniel Lee, at Winchester, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 19 December 1808. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Daniel Lee, at Winchester, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 29 June 1809. (Box-folder 2:4)
    A receipt for money received from Philip Lightfoot appears on the same sheet.
  - Robert I. Henry, at Baltimore, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 23 October 1809. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Francis Shinn, at Hillsborough, Highland County, Ohio, to Capt. Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 6 January 1810. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - W. S. Stone, at Fredericksburg, to Philip Lightfoot [?], 13 April 1810. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Daniel Lee to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 4 May 1810. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House to John Moss, at Philadelphia, 7 May 1810. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - S. P[?], at Falmouth, Stafford County to [?], October 1813. (Box-folder 2:5)
    Note: The account of Isaac Stone with James Vass appears on the same sheet.
  - James Vass to [?], 6 November 1813. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - John Browne Cutting, at Richmond, to Landon Nelson Carter, at Hartwood Academy, 10 April 1814., Mutilated. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - George Hoffman, at Baltimore, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 17 February 1816. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Lewis [?], at Alexandria, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 12 June 1816., Mutilated. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Elliot Muse, at Alexandria, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 16 January 1817. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - John Campbell, at Bourbon, Kentucky, to Major Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 6 April 1817. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - J. R. Ingersoll, at Philadelphia, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 16 November 1818. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - J. O. Evans to Major Philip Lightfoot, 28 January 1824. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - [?], at Clifton, to Major Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, 30 November 1824., Mutilated. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Jaquelin P. Taylor, at Richmond, to Judge R. H. Field, at Culpeper Court House, 23 March 1836. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - E. C. Richardson, at Richmond, to Philip Lightfoot, 13 May 1836., On same sheet with Jaquelin P. Taylor to Philip Lightfoot. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Jaquelin P. Taylor to Philip Lightfoot, On same sheet with E. C. Richardson, at Richmond, to Philip Lightfoot, 13 May 1836. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Jaquelin P. Taylor, at Richmond, to Philip Lightfoot, 11 July 1836. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Nancy F. Thompson, at Walnut Grove, to Margarett F. Patterson, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 10 December 1839. Postmarked Cloaver Dale, [Botetourt County], Virginia. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - W. J. Menefee, at Washington, Rappahannock County, to Philip Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 17 February 1843., Mutilated. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Susan M. M. Cook, at Tishamingo, Mississippi, to Major Philip Lightfoot, at Fairfax, Culpeper County, Virginia, 6 August 1843. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - John Pendleton to Major Philip Lightfoot. 1 July 1844., On same sheet with J. J. Crittenden to Philip Lightfoot. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - J. J. Crittenden to Philip Lightfoot, n.d., On same sheet with John Pendleton to Major Philip Lightfoot, 1 July 1844. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Sangston & Co., at Baltimore, to Philip Lightfoot, 21 October 1844. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - John J. Gorley to Edward Lightfoot, at Locust Dale, Madison County, Virginia, 30 March 1849. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - E. Lightfoot, at Gordonsville, Orange County, to his mother, Nancy Smith, at Locust Dale, Madison County, Virginia, 22 February 1850. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - William Baker, at Baltimore, to Philip Lightfoot, 8 January 1853. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Susan M[?], at Staunton, Virginia, to Edward Lightfoot, at Locust Dale, Madison County, 14 January 1856. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - National Executive Committee of the American Party, at Washington, to Edward Lightfoot, at Culpeper Court House, Virginia, 15 June 1856., Printed circular letter. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - H. R. T[?], at Alexandria, to Edward Lightfoot, 21 May 1860. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Thomas [?] to Edward Lightfoot, near Locust Dale, Madison County, Virginia, 7 July 1860., Mutilated. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Daniel Lee, at Woodstock, to Philip Lightfoot, n.d., Mutilated. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Frances Lightfoot, at Washington Town, Mason County, Kentucky, to her brother, Philip Lightfoot, Culpeper County, Virginia, n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)
    This letter contains an account of the trip to Kentucky.
  - John B. Lightfoot, Fleming County, Kentucky, to his brother, Capt. Philip Lightfoot, Culpeper County, Virginia, n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Molly Lightfoot, to her aunt, Ann Lightfoot, at Locust Dale, Madison County, Virginia, n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Philip Lightfoot to William Wirt and others, n.d., Mutilated. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Philip Lightfoot to [?], n.d., Two incomplete leters. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - William Lightfoot, in Kentucky, to his son, Capt. Philip Lightfoot, n.d., Mutilated. (Box-folder 2:5)
    Also a tinted photostat.
  - Mildred Nabb to Capt. Philip Lightfoot, at Woodstock, Virginia, n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)
  Series 3: Accounts and Invoices
- Accounts and Invoices, 1770-1855. (Box-folder 2:6-7 and 3:8)
  Alphabetically.
  - Culpeper County. Fee bills of the clerk and coroner, 1792-1832., 27 items. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Culpeper County. Fee bills of the jailor, 1805. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Culpeper County. Fee bills of the sheriff, 1803-1824., 18 items. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - (Edward) Ligthfoot. Invoices and receipts, 1799-1848., 11 items. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - (Philip) Lightfoot. Fee bills and receipts of sheriffs and clerks, 1803-1850., 66 items. (Box-folder 2:7)
  - (Philip) Lightfoot. Tax bills and receipts, 1803-1853., 21 items. (Box-folder 2:7)
  - (Philip) Lightfoot.Accounts, invoices, and receipts, 1789-1855., 134 items. (Box-folder 2:7)
    Includes a memorandum book.
  - (William) Lightfoot, 1770-1795., 2 items. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Madison County, fee bills of the clerk, 1802-1803., 2 items. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Orange County, fee bills of the clerk, 1817-1818., 2 items. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Thompson (Garland), 1788-1805., 8 items. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Accounts and invoices of other persons, 1789-1851., 41 items. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Unidentified and incomplete accounts and invoices, 1803-1854., 13 items. (Box-folder 3:8)
  Series 4: Papers Relating to Accounts Collected by Philip Lightfoot
- Papers Relating to Accounts Collected by Philip Lightfoot. (Box-folder 3:9-10 and 4:11-12)
  - Annin (Daniel), 1816-1817., 4 items. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Ashby (William), 1839., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Barbour (Mordecai), n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Bent (Lemuel), 1806., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Bradford (Samuel K.), n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Bramham (Nimrod), 1819-1822., 13 items. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Branham (Robert), 1805-1808., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Brown (Nimrod), assignee of John Rees, 1821-1823., 3 items. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Browning (Shadrach), 1807., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Butt (John), 1811., 3 items. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Camp (Robert), 1802-1804., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Campbell Ritchie & Co., 1810-1819., 3 items. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Cave (Benjamin), 1812., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Clarke (W.), n.d., 1 item. Mutilated. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Colvin (Daniel), 1806., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Croudson (Samuel), 1796-1802., 36 items. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Denton (John), 1810., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Duval, Keighler & Co., 1842-1843., 6 items. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Eichelberger (Jesse) and Co., 1810-1811., 2 items. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Fuller & Brown, 1805., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Gaines (Kemp), 1816, 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Glenn (John), 1819., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Goddard (John), 1808-1811., 11 items. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Guinn (Joshua), 1824-1825., 4 items. (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Hauge (Samuel), n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Hall & Company, 1837-1845., 9 items. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Hammer (Frederick), 1811., 2 items. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Harden (Samuel) and Co, 1810-1811., 5 items. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Thomas Harrison, trustee of Harrison & Brother, 1839., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Hawkins (John), n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Heathcote (John) estate, 1824-1827., 2 items. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Henry & Lindenberger, 1806-1810., 4 items. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Hoffman (George), 1810., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Hoffman (Jacob), 1803-1807., 5 items. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Hoffman (Peter, Jr.), 1807-1811., 12 items. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Holloway (Jesse), 1809., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Horner (Joseph P.), 1824-1825., 2 items. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Hume (Armistead), 1807., 1 item. (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Jackson (William S.), 1817-1818., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Jameson (John), 1803., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Jenkins (Walter), 1810-1823., 10 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Johnson & Dickey, 1832.1832., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Kay (James), 1819-1820., 7 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Kay (Robert), 1823., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Kerr (Matthew M.), 1841., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Lambert (William), 1806., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Leckie (William L.), 1803-1804., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Lee (Daniel), 1802-1804., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Lindenberger (G. F. and J.), 1809-1810., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Peter Hay, administrator of Lionberger (D.), 1818-1819., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Long (Brumfield), n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Lovell (John), assignee of John Gayle, 1816., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Lovell (Robert), 1833., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Lovell (William), 1804-1820., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - McDonald (William), 1806., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - McMullen (James), 1819., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - McNeale (John), 1816-1817., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Marshall (John W.), 1810., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Martin (James), 1821-1822., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Mathews (John), 1807-1811., 5 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Medley (Reuben), 1806., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Mitchell (John), 1838-1839., 4 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Morris (George), assignee of Humphreys and Carter, 1817., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Mullikin (B. D. and R.), 1819., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Mullikin (B. H.), 1816., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Norris (Richard), 1805., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Norris (William) and Son, 1828-1832., 8 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Executors of Parks (Richard), 1821., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Patterson (Joseph), 1816-1818., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Patton (Robert), 1809., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Pleasants (Joseph), 1805., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Riggs, Peabody & Co., 1824., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Robinson (Edward D.), 1842-1843., 11 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Rose (Jesse), 1805., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Rudasila (William), 1818., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Christian Farrer and John Roads, executors of Ruffner (Benjamin), 1816-1817., 6 items. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Ruffner (Joseph), 1795., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:11)
  - Schroeder (Henry), 1805-1810., 14 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Shaw & Tiffany, 1818-1820., 6 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Slaughter (Laurence), 1803., 1 item. Mutilated. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Stone (James, Jr.) & Co., 1817., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Strother (John), 1819., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Sturges & Sherman, 1819-1820., 8 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Tapp (Lewis), 1804-1816., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Tebbs (G. W.), 1803., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Thatcher (Elisha), 1803., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Thom (John), 1838-1843., 9 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Thornton (George A.), 1818., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Thornton (John), 1807-1808., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Tucker (Edward), 1810., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Tull (Richard Johnson), 1799., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Urquhart (Charles), 1813-1818., 2 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - John Wallace, executor of Wallace (Thomas), 1820., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Watkins (Sarah), 1802-1806., 14 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Wheeler (George), 1800., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Williams (Coleman), 1841-1843., 10 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Williams (William C.), 1791-1794., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Wilson (Stacey), 1803., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Windell (George W.), 1835., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Wirt (William), 1809., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Benjamin Wood, executor of Wood (Nehemiah), 1824., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Woodrow (Joshua) and Son, 1807-1809., 3 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Wright (Charles D.), 1810-1811., 5 items. (Box-folder 4:12)
  - Wright (John), 1812., 1 item. (Box-folder 4:12)